A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Middle East and Africa, Tunis, Tunisia Field Office Files FA645
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, International Division, Middle East and Africa, Tunis, Tunisia Field Office Files
1960-1978
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA645
25.2 Cubic Feet
Separated Materials
Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Conditions Governing Access
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement
Arranged in 8 series primarily by subject.
Collection arrangement is as follows:
Series I. Agriculture, 1962-1965, 1970-1975
Series II. Development Planning, 1961-1977
Series III. Education, 1960-1978
Series IV. General Reports, 1960-1973
Series V. General -- Subject Files, 1965-1971
Series VI. General Correspondence, 1963-1974
Series VII. Population, 1962-1976
Series VIII. Public Administration, 1964-1968
Biographical / Historical
The Ford Foundation's office in Tunis, Tunisia operated between 1961 and 1978. The Tunis Office served as the Foundation's base for North Africa programming and oversaw grants for the countries of Tunisia, Morocco, and Algeria. Programming chiefly focused on population, education, economic and social planning and administration, and agriculture.
- Information taken from The Ford Foundation/Population Council North Africa Population Program in Retrospect: 1963-1975 by Alain Marcoux, December 1975, Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 17727-19980 (FA739G), Report 019937.
Scope and Contents
Contains records related to agriculture, development planning, education, population and public administration, as well as field office correspondence and reports.
- Agriculture, 1962-1965, 1970-1975; I
  - Agriculture -- Algeria -- Correspondence, 1962-1966 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- Conferences and Seminars -- International Centers' Week (July 31-Aug 4, 1972) -- Memo Re: International Agricultural Research and Training, 1972 August 21 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- Conferences and Seminars -- Seminaire International sur le Pastoralisme (Algier, April 22-28, 1974), 1974 April 22-28 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- Conferences and Seminars -- Joint MEA-OLAC Agricultural Program Workshop (April 29-May 3, 1974), 1974 April 29-May 3 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- Conferences and Seminars -- Regional Wheat Meeting (Turkey, May 1974), 1974 May (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- Conferences and Seminars -- Second International Seminar on Change in Agriculture (Reading, September 9-19, 1974), 1974 September 9-19 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- Conferences and Seminars -- XIX International Dairy Congress (New Delhi, December (1974), 1974 December (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- Consultancy Visit by Drs. Edwards and Conklin, University of Oregon (to Tunisia and Algeria), 1973 July (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- General Information (correspondence with Lowell Hardin, proposed international centers), 1969-1974 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- General Information -- Lowell Hardin Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- General, 1969-1972 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- General -- CIMMYT -- Conference (Athens, February 16-17, 1974), 1974 February 16-17 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- General -- Correspondence -- Algeria, 1968-1972 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- General -- Correspondence -- Morocco, 1969-1972 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- General -- Correspondence -- Tunisia, 1968-1972 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- General -- Fertilizer Situation, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- General -- (World) Food Situation, 1973-1975 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- General -- Other Agencies, 1968-1970 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- General -- Other Agencies, 1970-1972 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- General -- Other Agencies -- OLC -- Development from Below Field Trip/Workshop (Ethiopia, October 1973), 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- General -- Program Strategy Review, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- Institut de Technologie Agricole -- Mostaganem, 1971-1976 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture -- Morocco -- Bureau Pedagogique -- Rabat Reports, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Agriculture -- Morocco -- Bureau Pedagogique -- Rabat Reports (1/2), 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Agriculture -- Morocco -- Bureau Pedagogique -- Rabat Reports (2/2), 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Agriculture -- Morocco -- Bureau Pedagogique -- Rabat, 1970 August-1972 December (Box 2)
  - Agriculture -- Project Evaluations -- Handwritten Notes, undated (Box 2)
  - Agriculture -- Project Proposals -- Association of Faculties of Agriculture in Africa (AFAA), 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Agriculture -- Project Proposals -- Rice -- Algeria, Morocco, and North Africa (other countries), 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Agriculture -- Project Proposals -- Training of Tunisian Mexican Wheat Extension Workers, 1971-1974 (Box 2)
  - Agriculture -- Training of Tunisian Mexican Wheat Extension Workers (Borgo-a-Mozzano, June 17-July 13, 1974) -- Reports and Results, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
  - Agriculture -- Tunisia -- Recyclage Center (#690-0505), 1970 (Box 2)
  - Agriculture -- Visit to Australia (Summer 1973) -- Tunisian and Algerian Officials (Box 2)
  - Agriculture -- "Vocational Agricultural Education in Tunisia and the Training of Intermediate Agricultural Cadres" by B.G. Moussouros (French and English versions), 1970 May (Box 2)
  - Agriculture -- "Vocational Agricultural Education in Tunisia and the Training of Intermediate Agricultural Cadres" by B.G. Moussouros and Notes Re: Agricultural Training Centers, 1970 (Box 2)
- Development Planning, 1961-1977; II
  - Development Planning -- Center for Research on Economic Development, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Development Planning -- Economic -- Tunisia -- Movement Jeunes Science Tunisie, 1973 August (Box 3)
  - Development Planning -- Public Management Review, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Development Planning and Administration -- General -- Information, 1969-1972 (Box 3)
  - Development Planning and Administration-- General -- Correspondence, 1969-1972 (Box 3)
  - Development Planning -- Report -- Notes on the Direction of Future Tunisian Planning and Possible Planning Assistance, 1970 July (Box 3)
  - Development Planning -- Report -- An Approach to Manpower Planning, 1970 July (Box 3)
  - Development Planning -- Social Science, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Development Planning -- General -- Other Agencies, 1973 January-July (Box 3)
  - Development Planning -- General -- Other Agencies -- L'Institut Atlantique/Instituto Affari Internazionali, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Development Planning -- General -- Other Agencies -- Resesarch Project on the Migration and Return of Professionals ("Brain Drain"), 1971 (Box 3)
  - Development Planning -- General -- Other Agencies -- Urban Studies Information, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Development Planning and Management -- General -- Other Agencies, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Development Planning and Management -- General Information (II), 1973 (Box 3)
  - Development Planning -- Schools of Public Administration (Algeria, Morocco, Tunisia), 1966-1969 (Box 3)
  - Development Planning and Administration -- General -- Reports, 1968-1972 (Box 4)
  - CAFRAD -- African Training and Research Center in Administration for Development, 1964-1968 (Box 4)
  - Development and Planning -- Public Administration -- General, 1961-1969 (Box 4)
  - Population and Development Policy --Ford Foundation/Rockefeller Research Program, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Development Planning and Management -- General -- Reports -- Simmons Report, 1968 May 20 (Box 4)
  - Development Management and Planning -- Correspondence II, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
  - Development Management and Planning -- Correspondence III, 1974-1976 (Box 5)
  - Organisation Maghrebine de Gestion (OMG), 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - Development and Management -- Conferences -- First Maghrebian Conference on Training in Enterprises, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Development Planning and Management -- Conferences and Seminars -- EFMD Conference/Turin, 1974 May 19-22 (Box 5)
  - Development Planning and Management -- Conferences and Seminars -- Executive Seminar on Employment Strategies, Washington, 1974 October 24 (Box 5)
  - Development Planning and Management -- Conferences and Seminars -- Miscellaneous, 1968-1976 (Box 5)
  - Development Planning and Management -- Project Proposal -- INPED, Algeria, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
  - Development Planning and Management -- Public Management Program Development -- Richard S. Roberts, Jr. -- Visit to the U.S., 1973 (Box 5)
  - Development and Planning -- Historia -- Algeria, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Development and Planning -- Project Proposals (Information Sheet and Miscellaneous), 1974 (Box 5)
  - Project Proposal -- Possible Consultancy for I.S.G. Dr. Khemakhem, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Development Planning and Management -- General Specified Files -- Management Strategy Review, 1973 September (Box 5)
  - National Institute of Productivity Management and Enterprise -- Training -- Tunisia, 1968-1971 (Box 5)
  - Development and Planning -- Urban Renewal -- Morocco, 1968-1972 (Box 5)
  - CODESRIA and Educational Development -- Memoranda re: Activities, Meetings, etc., 1972-1973 (Box 5)
- Education, 1960-1978; III
  - Center for Economic and Social Research -- University of Tunis, 1966-1968 (Box 6)
  - Center for Economic and Social Research -- Reports I, 1961-1967 (Box 6)
  - Center for Economic and Social Research (1/2), 1961-1964 (Box 6)
  - Center for Economic and Social Research (CERS) (2/2), 1968 (Box 6)
  - Education -- Assisting Educational and Cultural Development, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Education -- English Language in Tunisia, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Education -- Discretionary Grants -- Faculte de Lettres, Tunis -- English Plavers, 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Education and Research -- Discretionary Grants -- Ecole des Beaux Arts, Tunis, 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Education -- Carthage English Seminar, 1969-1973 (Box 6)
  - Education -- CAFRAD, 1970-1973 (Box 6)
  - Education -- Discretionry Award -- English Training, 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Education -- Discretionary Awards -- Representative's Contingency Fund, 1968-1969
  - Education -- General and Textbook Project, 1971-1974 (Box 7)
  - Education -- Ministry of Foreign Affairs -- CERES, 1975-1977 (Box 7)
  - Education -- Revue D'Histoire Maghrebine, 1975-1977 (Box 7)
  - Education -- IPSI, 1975-1977 (Box 7)
  - Stambouli, 1976-1977 (Box 7)
  - Education -- Textbook Project, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Education and Research -- Conferences and Seminars -- Miscellaneous, 1969-1971 (Box 7)
  - Education -- Summer Seminar, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Education and Research -- General Correspondence I, 1970-1972 (Box 7)
  - Education and Research -- General Correspondence II, 1973 January-August (Box 7)
  - Education -- General -- Seminars and Conferences, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Education and Research -- General Information I, 1969-1972 (Box 7)
  - Education and Research -- General Information II, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Education and Research -- General Information III, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Education and Research -- General Reports I, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Education and Research -- General Reports III, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Education and Research -- General Reports IV, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Travel and Study -- TOEFL/Algeria -- Kouloughli, 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Education -- Travel and Study -- General File, 1970-1971 (Box 7)
  - Education -- General Information -- History, 1967-1973 (Box 8)
  - Education -- General -- Restrospective Study and Harrison/Fox Correspondence, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Education -- Instituts de Technologies, undated (Box 8)
  - Education -- Migration -- Iranians, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Education -- Report -- Ford Foundation Consulting Mission in re: Request from Algerian Ministry of Higher Education, 1975 (Box 8)
  - Education and Research -- Reports -- Project Proposals -- Social Sciences/Migration of Scholars -- Micaud, 1973-1975 (Box 8)
  - Education -- Special Topics - -Institut de Presse Tunis, 1973-1975 (Box 8)
  - Education and Research -- English for Special Purposes -- Linguistic Institute, 1974-1975 (Box 8)
  - Education -- Tunis -- National School of Administration -- Reports II, 1968-1973 (Box 8)
  - Education -- Tunis -- National School of Administration -- Correspondence I, 1962-1966 (Box 8)
  - Education -- Tunis -- National School of Administration -- Correspondence II, 1967-1974 (Box 8)
  - Education -- General -- Information -- Tunisia, 1972-1973 (Box 8)
  - Education -- General Information -- Algeria, 1971-1975 (Box 8)
  - Education -- Algeria -- Recruitment Project -- Professors, 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Education and Research -- Algerian Language Institute -- Survey, 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Education -- Report -- English Language Teaching in Algeria, 1975 September (Box 8)
  - Education -- Algeria -- Miscellaneous, 1975 (Box 8)
  - Education -- Algeria -- Scholarships, 1962-1965 (Box 8)
  - Algers Linguistics Project, 1968 (Box 8)
  - Algers Linguistics Project, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Algers Linguistics Project, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Education and Research -- General Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 9)
  - Education -- General -- Other Agencies -- American Friends of the Middle East and/or Maghreb -- Mrs. Patricia Payne, 1974 January (Box 9)
  - Education and Research -- General -- Other Information, 1974-1976 (Box 9)
  - Education -- Conference -- Social Sciences -- North Africa, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Education and Research -- Conferences and Seminars -- Miscellaneous, 1974-1975 (Box 9)
  - Education -- Tunisian Desert Biome Project -- Novikoff, 1974-1978 (Box 9)
  - Education -- General Information -- Morocco, 1972-1976 (Box 9)
  - Education -- Fundamental Arabic Project -- Seminar and Proposal (Olson, Beirut), 1973-1974 (Box 9)
  - Education -- General -- Other Agencies -- Overseas Liason Committee -- American Council on Education, 1974-1975 (Box 9)
  - Education -- General -- Other Agencies II, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Education -- English for Special Purposes Conference -- Hannamet, Tunisia, 1975 February 25-28 (Box 9)
  - Education -- ELT Project -- Correspondence, 1973 May-1974 January (Box 9)
  - Education -- English Language Textbook Development for Secondary Schools -- Reports (E1690-0742) (1/2), 1972 (Box 9)
  - Education -- English Language Textbook Development for Secondary Schools -- Reports (E1690-0742) (2/2), 1972 (Box 9)
  - Education -- English Language Textbook Development for Secondary Schools -- (690-0742) -- Reports (1/2), 1969-1972 (Box 9)
  - Education -- English Language Textbook Development for Secondary Schools -- (690-0742) -- Reports (2/2), 1969-1972 (Box 9)
  - Education -- English Language Textbook Development for Secondary Schools -- (729-0046) -- Reports, 1974-1975 (Box 9)
  - Education -- English Language Textbook Development for Secondary Schools -- Financial, 1974 June-1975 (Box 9)
  - Education -- ELT Project, 1960-1978; III.1 (Box 10)
    - ELT Project -- Requests for Grant Action, 1963-1967 (Box 10)
    - ELT Project -- Summer Seminar, 1970 (Box 10)
    - Education - English Language Textbook (ELT) Project -- Correspondence IV, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
    - ELT Project -- Textbook Project IV bis -- Summer Course -- Bizerta, 1973 (Box 10)
    - ELT Project -- Textbook Project -- Tunisia -- IV bis -- Seminars, 1971-1972 (Box 10)
    - ELT Project -- Group Study Tours, 1973 (Box 10)
    - ELT Project -- Textbook Project Tunisia -- Budget, 1973-1974 (Box 10)
    - ELT Project -- Algeria -- R.M. Payne Trip, 1974 May (Box 10)
    - Report -- The Economy of the Maghreb, 1963 (Box 10)
    - Study of the Creation of the Tunisian University, undated (Box 10)
    - La Situation de L'Enseignement en Tunisie 1958-1964, 1964 May-June (Box 10)
    - A Ten Year Prospect of School Attendance, undated (Box 10)
    - Situation Scolaire, 1961 June (Box 10)
    - New Conception of Education in Tunisia 1958-1959, circa 1960 (Box 10)
    - Situation de L'enseignement, 1962-1963 (Box 10)
    - Universite de Tunis -- Fondation et Premieres Realisations, 1960-1961 (Box 10)
    - English Language Education in North Africa -- English Textbook Project (DAP 759-0800) (1/2), 1974-1978 (Box 10)
    - English Language Education in North Africa -- English Textbook Project (DAP 759-0800) (2/2), 1974-1978 (Box 10)
    - Education -- English for Special Purposes Conference in Hammamet (1/2), 1974-1975 (Box 10)
    - Education -- English for Special Purposes Conference in Hammamet (2/2), 1974-1975 (Box 10)
    - Linguistics -- Summer Seminar -- Algeria, Tunisia, Morocco, 1969-1970 (Box 10)
- General Reports, 1960-1973; IV
  - General -- Information -- North Africa Review, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Middle East and Africa (MEA) Program Report, 1973 (Box 11)
  - General -- Reports -- Quarterly (Tunis Field Office), 1972-1973 (Box 11)
  - Quarterly Reports -- Tunis, 1972 (Box 11)
  - General -- Reports -- Algeria/Tunisia/Morocco, 1968-1971 (Box 11)
  - General -- Reports -- Administrative Reports, 1966-1970 (Box 11)
  - General -- Reports -- Evaluation Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 11)
  - North African Program Annual Report, 1970 November (Box 11)
  - North African Program Annual Report, 1971 (Box 11)
  - North African Program Annual Report, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation Annual Reports 1969 Distribution, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation Annual Reports 1970 Distribution, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation Annual Reports 1971 Distribution, 1972 (Box 11)
  - General -- Reports -- Annual Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 11)
  - General -- Government Relations -- Tunisia, 1968-1971 (Box 11)
  - General -- Government Relations -- Algeria, 1965-1971 (Box 11)
  - General -- Government Relations -- Morocco, 1960-1972 (Box 11)
  - Tunis Field Office -- Local Ford Foundation Correspondence Left by George Sheldon, 1968-1970 (Box 11)
  - Tunis Field Office -- Inter-office Memoranda, 1969-1971 (Box 11)
  - Tunis Field Office -- Financial Management Reviews and Internal Accounting Control -- Price Waterhouse and Co., 1963-1971 (Box 11)
  - Special Reports -- Comptroller's Office, 1970-1971 (Box 11)
- General -- Subject Files, 1965-1971; V
  - International Division Conference -- Mexico -- Representatives Meeting, 1968-1969 (Box 12)
  - International Division -- Representatives Meeting -- Nairobi, 1968 (Box 12)
  - International Division -- Representatives Meeting -- Tunis, 1965 (Box 12)
  - Education -- New Delhi Conference, 1971 October (Box 12)
  - International Division -- New Delhi Conference -- Discussion Paper, 1971 October (Box 12)
- General Correspondence, 1963-1974; VI
  - Correspondence -- General -- Other Agencies -- Miscellaneous, 1973-1974 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence -- General -- Other Agencies -- Divers, 1970-1972 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence -- General -- Other Agencies -- Morocco, 1972 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence -- General -- Other Agencies -- Tunisia, 1968-1972 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence -- General -- Other Agencies -- Algeria, 1972 (Box 12)
  - General -- Conferences and Seminars -- MEA Economics Program Advisors Conference -- New York, 1971 September (Box 12)
  - Correspondence -- Administrative Conference -- Nairobi, 1969 July (Box 12)
  - Correspondence -- General -- Non-Program Conferences -- Divers, 1969 (Box 12)
  - Chronological Correspondence -- Algiers, 1971 (Box 12)
  - Marshall, R., 1969-1970 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence -- Brown, 1969-1971 (Box 12)
  - Brucher, Mr. Felix, 1970-1971 (Box 12)
  - General -- LeMelle, Wilbert J. -- General, 1973 April-September (Box 12)
  - General -- LeMelle, Wilbert J. -- General, 1973 October-December (Box 12)
  - General -- LeMelle, Wilbert -- Personal, 1973 (Box 12)
  - General -- Guillaume deSpoelberch's Fairwell Letters, 1973 (Box 12)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1963 February 16-September 30 (Box 13)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1963 October-1964 March (Box 13)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1964 April-September (Box 13)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1964 October-1965 April (Box 13)
  - Chronological Correspondence (1/2), 1968 January-April (Box 13)
  - Chronological Correspondence (2/2), 1968 January-April (Box 13)
  - Chronological Correspondence (1/2), 1968 May-August (Box 13)
  - Chronological Correspondence (2/2), 1968 May-August (Box 13)
  - Chronological Correspondence (1/2), 1968 August-December (Box 13)
  - Chronological Correspondence (2/2), 1968 August-December (Box 13)
  - Chronological Correspondence (1/2), 1969 January-March (Box 13)
  - Chronological Correspondence (2/2), 1969 January-March (Box 13)
  - Chronological Correspondence (1/2), 1969 April-June (Box 13)
  - Chronological Correspondence (2/2), 1969 April-June (Box 13)
  - Chronological Correspondence (1/2), 1969 July-October (Box 13)
  - Chronological Correspondence (2/2), 1969 July-October (Box 13)
  - Administrative Chronological Correspondence, 1973 January-October (Box 14)
  - Program Chronological Correspondence, 1973 January-June (Box 14)
  - Program Chronological Correspondence, 1973 July-December (Box 14)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files -- Algeria, 1973 (Box 14)
- Population, 1962-1976; VII
  - Algeria Family Planning Program -- Demography Project I, 1964-1965 (Box 15)
  - Algeria Family Planning Program -- Demography Project II, 1964-1966 (Box 15)
  - Algeria Family Planning Program -- Demography Project III, 1966-1967 (Box 15)
  - Algeria Family Planning Program -- Demography Project IV, 1967-1968 (Box 15)
  - Algeria Family Planning Program -- Demographic Assistance, 1968 January-1970 February (Box 15)
  - Population -- Demographic Assistance in Algeria -- Reports I, 1971-1973 (Box 15)
  - Population -- Demographic Assistance in Algeria -- Reports II, 1973 (Box 15)
  - Population -- Demographic Assistance in Algeria -- II, 1970-1971 (Box 15)
  - Population -- Demographic Assistance in Algeria -- III (1/2), 1971-1973 (Box 15)
  - Population -- Demographic Assistance in Algeria -- III (2/2), 1971-1973 (Box 15)
  - Population -- Demographic Assistance in Algeria -- IV, 1973-1974 (Box 15)
  - Population -- Demography Algeria -- "La Republique" Article (June 23, 1973) -- Translation/Distribution (June 1974), 1973-1974 (Box 15)
  - Population -- General -- Migration -- Algeria, 1973-1974 (Box 15)
  - Algeria Family Planning Report ("Les Imperatifs d'une Planification Familiale en Algerie") by Pierre Pradervand et al., 1966 April (Box 15)
  - Survey of Family Planning Knowledge, Attitudes, and Practice in Algeria (#670-0134), 1967-1970 (Box 15)
  - Family Planning and Demography -- Maghreb (North Africa) -- Reports (1/3), 1962-1969 (Box 16)
  - Family Planning and Demography -- Maghreb (North Africa) -- Reports (2/3), 1962-1969 (Box 16)
  - Family Planning and Demography -- Maghreb (North Africa) -- Reports (3/3), 1962-1969 (Box 16)
  - Population -- Kingdom of Morocco -- National Family Planning Program -- Reports I, 1965-1967 (Box 16)
  - Population -- Kingdom of Morocco -- National Family Planning Program -- Reports II, 1967-1970 (Box 16)